# ANDY MUEHLHAUSEN

andv@andvmule.com

765-543-6588

www.andvmule.com

I'm a quirky combination of computer scientist and sound designer with a passion for inventing fun and meaningful social interactions.

Interactive	Experience	Designs
IIILEIACLIVE	FYDELICITE	Desidiis

2012	MUGIC Network-Streamed Graphics Protocol Received a grant to research platform-independen	CALIT2 t stateless and stateful ne	San Diego, CA etwork-streamed graphics.
2012	Crossing Boundaries First live usage of MUGIC (with JOGL, and MaxMS mega-wall of 16 computers and 32 HD monitors. U		
2011-2012	Recombinant Media Labs – CineChamber Live audio/visual reactive installations and perform	CRCA nances in a 10-projector a	San Diego, CA nd 16-speaker configuration.
2011	PQ Production: Ad Infinitum <sup>3</sup> Designed sound and programmed a game engine multiplayer game that opened the 2011 Prague Qu	,	, ,

Rock Band Mix Producer Sonic Iguana Studios Lafayette, IN

Provided stem tracks, submixes, full mixes, and referencing mixes for the Anti-Flag song "We Are the One" to

be recreated as downloadable content on Guitar Hero and Rock Band games.

## **Recent Work History**

2010

CALIT2 Researcher	Radio Show Producer	UCSD Teacher	Recording Engineer
UCSD – San Diego, CA	Changing Lanes Radio	Undergrad Design	Sonic Iguana Studios
2011-Current	2012	2011-Current	2009-2011

### Notable Sound Designs

2011	U.S. Tour U.S. Tour	sound effects designer theme song	Madagascar Live Gazillion Bubble Show
2011-2012	U.C. San Diego	composer, sound designer asst. sound design composer, sound designer	Elizabeth I Spring Awakening Gas House Baby
2010	Hope Smmr Rep. Holland, MI	composer, sound designer asst. sound designer	The Brand New Kid Into the Woods
2008-2011	Purdue University W Lafayette, IN	composer, sound designer composer, sound designer composer, producer	DANCLAB, Fall/Spring Dance Works Top Girls SNAK ATAK

#### Notable Album Credits

2011	Suckerbox	Soon Come	editor, tambourines	Go-Kart Records
2011	Horace Pinker	Local State Inertia	editor, drum synths	<b>Enemy One Records</b>
2011	Dusty Trip	D.I.Y.	tracker, editor, vox	Speed Records
2010	Svetlanas	Svetlanas	tracker, editor, guitars	Vampata
2008	Squirtgun	Fade to Bright	backing vox	Honest Don's

#### Other Skills

Programming Languages:	Java, C, C++, QT, OpenGL, FFMPEG, VST, Max/MSP, PD, JS, SQL, HTML, Kinect, Arduino
Software:	Touch Designer, Digital Performer, Ableton Live, QLab, SFX, Studio Manager, Sony Acid,

Yamaha M7&DM2000, Mackies, Waves Mercury, Heaps of Synths, OS, Windows, Linux

Proficient Instruments: Drums, Mallets, Electric Bass, Upright Bass, Guitar, Piano, Banjo

Jobs from earlier in life: landscaper, pizza maker, bar cook, spring maker, semi-trailer floor maker, promotions, more.

#### Education

Pursuing – M.F.A. **Theatre (Sound Design)**; **University of California, San Diego** – San Diego, CA (expected graduation 2014) Received – B.S. **Computer Science**; Minors: Theatre Technology & Design, Physics; **Purdue University** – West Lafayette, IN